Frank C. Laubach Collection
Frank C. Laubach Collection
- Projects, domestic
  - Research, miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 213)
  - Research proposal (Box 213)
  - Resource book, preparation of material for readers of limited ability (Box 213)
  - Simple English, articles re (Box 213)
  - Sketches (Box 213)
  - Slide shows, scripts (Box 213)
  - South Carolina, state literacy (Box 213)
  - Southern Rural Training Project, 1962 (Box 213)
  - Speech sounds, how to make, 1968 (Box 213)
  - Spelling (Box 213)
  - Stanford Achievement Test, 1965 (Box 213)
  - State Committee Chairman (Box 213)
  - State literacy organizations (Box 213)
  - State prisons, "An Experiment on Education", 1961 (Box 213)
  - Streamlined English word list (Box 213)
  - Students, foreign (Box 213)
  - Summer Institute of Literacy, 1968 (Box 213)
  - Syracuse University Library of Continuing Education, 1966 (Box 213)
  - Syracuse University School of Education (Box 214)
  - Syracuse University School of Journalism, 2 folders (Box 214)
  - Tape catalogs (Box 214)
  - Tape recording scripts (Box 214)
  - Teacher training
    - Evaluations, 2 folders (Box 214)
    - "Model School System", 1966 (Box 214)
    - Southern California (Box 214)
  - Teacher training, Laubach Literacy Fund, general (Box 214)
  - Teacher training conferences, regional, 1966-1968 (Box 214)
  - Teacher training workshops (Box 214)
  - Teaching, volunteer (Box 214)
  - "Teaching Adults" (Box 215)
  - Teaching Aids
    - "A Glossary for English the New Way," Stafford, V. H., 1962 (Box 215)
    - "An Easy Way to Better Reading," Valiant, M. (Box 215)
    - "Applied Mathematics" Book II, Hooker, Margaret (Box 215)
    - "Be Informed" Series (Box 215)
    - "Building Your Language Power", 1965 (Box 215)
    - "Building Your Language Power," guide to, 1965 (Box 215)
    - Charts and stories, materials for (Box 215)
    - "Christ, the Source of Our Power," Laubach, F., 1962 (Box 215)
    - "Each One Teach One" primers
      - [General] (Box 215)
      - Brochure (Box 215)
      - Complete edition (Box 215)
      - Prospectus, 1963 (Box 216)
    - Educational Developmental Laboratories English (Box 216)
    - "English the New Way Basic Phonics for," Laubach, F., 1969 (Box 216)
    - "English the New Way," Laubach, F. draft, lessons 1-20, 1969
      - Notes (Box 216)
      - Preparation (Box 216)
      - Readings (Box 216)
      - Teachers' manual, Hoff, Olive and Franklin (Box 216)
      - Explanations of (Box 216)
      - Sentence patterns in, Laubach, F. (Box 216)
      - Teacher's Guide to, Laubach, F. (Box 216)
      - Transparencies for (Box 216)
    - "Learn English the New Way," Laubach, F.
      - Revised ed. Book I, 1964 (Box 217)
      - Book II, 1960; 1962 (Box 217)
      - Revised ed., Book II, 1964 (Box 217)
      - Book II, Students' workbook, layout, 1964 (Box 217)
      - Workbook, Book I, 1965 (Box 218)
    - "New Ingglish Fonetic Alfubet," Laubach, F. (Box 219)
    - "New Streamlined English Series"
      - Corrections c.1967, 2 folders (Box 219)
      - Correlated reader #4 Laubach, F. and Kirk, E. M. (Box 219)
      - Correlated reader #5 (Box 219)
    - "New Streamlined English Series, Read the Easy Way," Laubach, F. dummies (Box 219)
    - "New Streamlined English Series" guides to, draft, 1967 (Box 219)
    - "New Streamlined English Series"
      - Materials for, 1967 (Box 219)
      - Orig. manuscripts, 1962 (Box 220)
      - Revisions, 1967 (Box 220)
      - Skill Book I c., 1960 (Box 220)
      - Book I, 1963-1964 (Box 220)
      - Skill Book I. orig. manuscripts, 1965 (Box 220)
      - Skill Book I, 1966 (Box 220)
      - Skill Book I, teacher's manual (Box 220)
      - Skill Books 1-3, teacher's manual for, abridged ed., 1967 (Box 220)
    - "New Streamlined English Series," Skill Books 1-5
      - Teacher's manual for, 1965 (Box 221)
      - Skill Book 2
        - Original manuscripts, 1965 (Box 221)
        - Teacher's manual, 1966 (Box 221)
      - Skill Book 3
        - Edited manuscripts, 1965 (Box 222)
        - Teacher's manual for, 1966; 1967 (Box 222)
      - Skill Book 4, 1966
        - Draft (Box 222)
        - Original edition manuscripts, 1965 (Box 223)
        - Revised manuscripts, 1967 (Box 223)
        - Teacher's manual for (Box 223)
        - Typesetting copy c., 1967 (Box 223)
      - Skill Book 5
        - Original edition manuscripts, 1965 (Box 223)
        - Revised edition, 1967 (Box 223)
        - [General], 1967 (Box 223)
        - Printer's copy, 1969 (Box 223)
        - Teacher's manual for (Box 224)
        - Teacher's manual for, 1967 (Box 224)
      - Skill Book 6, 1967 (Box 224)
    - "New Streamlined English Series, Read the Easy Way," Laubach, F.
      - Experimental ed., 1963 (Box 224)
      - Teacher's manual, 1963 (Box 224)
    - "New Streamlined English Series"
      - Slides (Box 224)
      - Stories for Laubach, F. and Kirk, E. M. (Box 224)
      - Story of Jesus, Book IX (Box 225)
      - Student's work book, 1964 (Box 225)
      - Teacher's manual and introduction (Box 225)
      - Tests for, draft, 1967 (Box 225)
      - Tests for, 1967; 2 folders (Box 225)
    - "New Streamlined English Series, Write the Easy Way," Laubach, F., Books I, II, IV dummy (Box 225)
    - Phonics, the Wallace Technique in (Box 226)
    - "Reading Readiness Charts and Stories," Laubach, F., 1955 (Box 226)
    - "Readings in Literature," teacher's guide for "Streamlined English", 1967 (Box 226)
    - "Streamlined English,"
      - Lesson plans for, 1962 (Box 226)
      - Materials re (Box 226)
      - Reading readiness charts and stories, 1955 (Box 226)
      - Revised edition, edited copies circa, 1955 (Box 226)
      - Revision for (Box 226)
      - Teacher's Guide and summaries of television lessons, 1960-1962 (Box 226)
      - Teacher's manual for, 1960 (Box 226)
      - Charts (Box 226)
    - "Streamlined English, Frank Laubach's," Wolf, W.C. (Box 227)
    - "Streamlined English Lessons"
      - Lessons 1-50, 3 folders (Box 227)
      - Teacher's Manual, Laubach, F., 1945 (Box 227)
    - "Streamlined English Series, Story of Jesus," Stage II, Books 1-12, revision, Laubach, F. (Box 227)
    - "Streamlined Reading," teacher's guide to (Box 227)
    - "Streamlined Spelling," McKeon, D. (Box 227)
    - "Streamlined Spelling," McKeon, D. (Box 228)
    - "Streamlined Writing" (Box 228)
    - "Teaching English as a Second Language" (Box 228)
    - "Teaching Helps," Laubach, F. 1968 • (Box 228)
    - "Words in Color," questions concerning, Gategno, C. (Box 228)
    - "Writing Lessons for the Student of the Laubach Methods," Literacy Center, Koinonia Foundation (Box 228)
  - Teaching Aids, sketches for (Box 228)
  - Teachers, literacy lists, 1966 (Box 228)
  - Teaching "English the New Way" (Box 228)
  - Teaching filmstrips (Box 228)
  - Teaching illiterates, Girl Scouts (Box 228)
  - Teaching report forms (Box 228)
  - Teaching reports, 1962 (Box 228)
  - Teaching reports: Bell, Alta, 1963 (Box 228)
  - Teaching writing, 1957-1962 (Box 228)
  - Teaching, radiophonic (Box 228)
  - Television literacy
    - "Adding the Easy Way", 1959-1960 (Box 228)
    - General (Box 228)
    - "Let's Learn to Pray" (Box 229)
    - "New Streamlined English," Memphis WKNO, 1965 (Box 229)
    - Operation Alphabet (Box 229)
    - "Reading the Easy-TV Way" (Box 229)
    - "Reading the Easy-TV Way," teacher's guide, Laubach, F. (Box 229)
    - "Streamlined Reading," WKNO-TV scrapbook of press clippings, 1958 (Box 229)
    - "Streamlined Writing Book", 1958 (Box 229)
    - Tennessee, WKNO (Box 229)
  - Television literacy reports and information re (Box 229)
  - Television literacy teacher's guides, 1960 (Box 229)
  - Television literacy program material, 1958-1963 (Box 229)
  - Television literacy proposal, 1963 (Box 229)
  - Television literacy workshops, script for, Blankenship, M. (Box 229)
  - Training and research, 1962 (Box 230)
  - Training Courses, A Study of Participants in, Laubach Literacy, 1965 (Box 230)
  - Training courses, Laubach Literacy (Box 230)
  - Union Organization (Box 230)
  - United States, tour of, Yudelowitz, Ruth, 1961 (Box 230)
  - U.S. Government
    - Civil disorder (Box 230)
    - Education, Office of (Box 230)
    - Education, Office of, compiled report (Box 230)
    - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of (Box 230)
    - Interior, Department of (Box 230)
    - Manpower contracts
      - I-II, 2 folders (Box 230)
      - III (Box 231)
    - Miscellaneous, 1957-1958 (Box 231)
    - National Service Program, facts on the proposed, 1963 (Box 231)
    - Presidential Address, 1960 (Box 231)
    - Representatives, House of, 1969 (Box 231)
    - Social Security (Box 231)
    - VISTA (Box 231)
  - Visual aids, transparencies (Box 231)
  - Voter registration (Box 231)
  - Washington, D. C., literacy (Box 231)
  - Wheaton College (Box 231)
  - Williams Laboratories (Box 231)
  - Women in literacy (Box 231)
  - Word lists (Box 231)
  - Workshop, Teacher Training, 1967 (Box 231)
  - Workshop and Training Conference (Box 231)
  - Workshop evaluation, 1964-1966; 2 folders (Box 232)
  - Workshop evaluation sheets, 1964-1966 (Box 232)
  - Workshop records (Box 232)
  - Workshop standards (Box 232)
  - Workshop test (Box 232)
  - Workshops
    - Certificate records (Box 232)
    - Certificate records, Florida, 1965 (Box 232)
    - General (Box 232)
    - Personal data for participants, 1963-1964 (Box 232)
    - Reports (Box 233)
    - Schedules (Box 233)
    - Teachers trained, 1968 (Box 233)
  - World literacy statistics (Box 233)
  - Youth, religion (Box 233)
  - Youth Leadership Training, 1965 (Box 233)
- Projects, overseas
  - Afghanistan, 2 folders (Box 235)
  - Afghanistan, 1964; 2 folders (Box 235)
  - Afghanistan: Literacy Pilot Project sample lesson, 1965 (Box 235)
  - Afghanistan, Associated Students of, in U.S. (Box 235)
  - Afghanistan Mission, 1967 (Box 235)
  - Afghanistan Research Center (Box 235)
  - Africa Adult Literacy Program
    - Congo (Box 236)
    - Congo-French primer, Ward, Ginger, 1951-1964 (Box 236)
    - Egypt (Box 236)
    - Ethiopia (Box 236)
    - General, 2 folders (Box 236)
    - Ghana (Box 236)
    - Ghana, "An experiment in Readability", 1957 (Box 236)
    - Kenya, 3 folders (Box 236)
    - Kenya, J.J. Dames (Box 236)
    - Kenya Literacy Center, 3 folders (Box 237)
    - Kenya literacy evangelism (Box 237)
    - Kenya Literacy Mission (Box 237)
    - Kenya Literacy Mission Handbook, 1965 (Box 237)
    - Kenya literacy organization (Box 237)
    - Kenya Literacy Project (Box 237)
    - Kenya Workshop Evaluations: J.J. Dames (Box 237)
    - Liberia (Box 238)
    - Literacy (Box 238)
    - Mali, notes on, Laubach, Robert (Box 238)
    - Mali Plan for Community Development (Box 238)
    - Morrill, Louise (Box 238)
    - Nigeria
      - General, 1962-1966 (Box 238)
      - Literacy (Box 238)
      - Literacy teachers (Box 238)
      - Sabo, Joe (Box 238)
      - Training evaluation (Box 238)
    - Nigeria Adult Literacy Project (Box 239)
    - Nigeria, University of (Box 239)
    - Operation Upgrade (Box 239)
    - Rhodesia (Box 239)
    - Rhodesia, Northern (Box 239)
    - Sierra Leone, 1964-1965 (Box 239)
    - Somalia, development (Box 239)
    - Statistics, literacy (Box 239)
    - Sudan (Box 239)
    - Swaziland (Box 239)
    - Tanganyika (Box 239)
  - Africa, South: Leader Exchange Program Operation Upgrade (Box 239)
  - Afro-lit
    - Conference, 3 folders (Box 240)
    - Newsletter, 1969 (Box 240)
    - Nairobi, Kenya, 1968 (Box 240)
    - Seminar (Box 240)
  - Annual report, 1964-1965 (Box 240)
  - Appendices, 1962 (Box 240)
  - Asia Society (Box 240)
  - Asia, Southeast, literacy contacts, 1961-1963 (Box 240)
  - Bolivia (Box 241)
  - Boyer, Gilbert (Box 241)
  - Brazil
    - General
      - 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 241)
      - Proposal for Literacy Training and Research (Box 241)
      - Reports and proposals, 1963-1969 (Box 241)
      - Roberts, Byron (Box 241)
    - Progress report for, 1964-1965 (Box 241)
  - British Honduras (Box 241)
  - Budrow, Theodore, "Alphabetizacion en America Latina" (Box 241)
  - Burma (Box 241)
  - Cambodia (Box 241)
  - China, Hong Kong, 1970 (Box 241)
  - Colombia
    - [General], 2 folders (Box 241)
    - [General], 4 folders (Box 242)
    - Educational television, 1966 (Box 262)
    - Literacy Attitudes Survey, Caswell, Robert and Cortright, Richard (Box 262)
  - Colombia
    - Antioquia, University of (Robert Caswell), 1967-1968 (Box 242)
    - Boyer, Gilbert, 1962-1963; 1964 (Box 242)
    - Caswell, Robert, 1966 (Box 242)
    - Friedman, Robert, 1964-1965 (Box 242)
    - La Picota Prison literacy, 1964 (Box 243)
    - Pearson, Irving, 1965; 1966 (Box 243)
    - Television education, 1965-1966 (Box 243)
  - Colombia, Medellin, 1966 (Box 243)
  - Contacts, literacy (Box 243)
  - Costa Rica (Box 243)
  - Ecuador
    - [General], 6 folders (Box 244)
    - Pearson, Irving, 1966 (Box 244)
    - Guayaquil (Box 244)
    - Quito, 1964-1965 (Box 245)
  - Filmstrips, Portuguese (Box 245)
  - Foreign aid (Box 245)
  - Foreign aid, information re (Box 245)
  - Foreign students in the United States (Box 245)
  - Foreign students, reports from, 1962 (Box 245)
  - Fund allocations (Box 245)
  - Guatemala
    - [General], 1962-1964; 2 folders (Box 245)
    - Sigman, Hal (Box 245)
  - Haiti (Box 245)
  - Honduras, 1962 (Box 245)
  - Hong Kong (Box 246)
  - Hunger, world (Box 246)
  - India
    - Bengal Social Service League (Box 246)
    - General, 1959-1960; undated; 4 folders (Box 246)
    - High, Ellen (Box 246)
    - John, A. K. (Box 246)
    - Literacy House, Lucknow (Box 247)
    - Leonard, Benjamin, 1962-1963 (Box 247)
  - India, Kerala (Box 247)
  - India, literacy in (Box 247)
  - Indian Journal of Adult Education (Box 247)
  - Indonesia (Box 247)
  - International Programs Community Development (Box 247)
  - Iran, Long-range Literacy Program (Box 247)
  - Israel itineraries, general (Box 247)
  - Japan (Box 247)
  - Jordan, 1955 (Box 247)
  - Kenya (Box 247)
  - Korea, 1962 (Box 247)
  - Ladder of Literacy, Spanish (Box 248)
  - Land reform (Box 248)
  - Language materials (Box 248)
  - Languages, shelf lists (Box 248)
  - Languages in which lessons have been prepared (Box 248)
  - Latin America, general, 3 folders (Box 248)
  - Lists of projects (Box 248)
  - Literacy Associates
    - Africa (Box 248)
    - Asia (Box 248)
    - Latin America (Box 248)
  - Literacy literature needs (Box 248)
  - Literacy materials, primers (Box 248)
  - Literacy Training and Research, Plan for Beginning Set of Materials for (Box 248)
  - Malaya (Box 248)
  - Mali, "An Open Letter...", 1962 (Box 248)
  - Manual of Operation (Box 248)
  - Maps (Box 248)
  - Mexico
    - de Renteria, Ana Maria, 1964 (Box 249)
    - General, 1956-1965; undated; 4 folders (Box 249)
    - Baja, California, 1962 (Box 249)
    - Tijuana, 1963-1964; undated; 2 folders (Box 249)
    - Valle de Bravo, 1961-1964 (Box 249)
  - Middle East (Box 250)
  - Migration (Box 250)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1967 (Box 250)
  - Missionaries, articles re (Box 250)
  - Missionary agencies, directory of (Box 250)
  - Near East, reports (Box 250)
  - Needs and opportunities, 1966 (Box 250)
  - Needs and requests for aid (Box 250)
  - Needs and support (Box 250)
  - Nepal literacy, 1966 (Box 250)
  - New literates, materials for
    - "Anand the Wise Man" vol. II (Box 250)
    - "Anand the Wise Man", 1952 (Box 262)
    - Spanish, 2 folders (Box 250)
    - Spanish book lists (Box 250)
  - Operation Upgrade (Box 251)
  - Pakistan
    - Bivar, H.G.S., 2 folders (Box 251)
    - General, 1963; undated; 5 folders (Box 251)
    - Literacy Conference, evaluation of (Box 252)
  - Pakistan, East, 1963-1965 (Box 252)
  - Panama (Box 252)
  - Paraguay (Box 252)
  - Peace Corps
    - Afghanistan (Box 252)
    - Brazil (Box 252)
    - Central America (Box 252)
    - Colombia
      - I-III, 3 folders (Box 252)
      - IV (Box 253)
    - Colombia Literacy Project (Box 253)
    - Colombia Proposal (Box 253)
    - Colombia teacher training (Box 253)
    - Contracting Manual (Box 253)
    - Directories and sample contracts (Box 253)
    - Ecuador (Box 253)
    - Evaluation of Trainees (Box 253)
    - General, 1961-1964; undated; 7 folders (Box 254)
    - Mexico (Box 254)
    - Pakistan (Box 254)
    - Proposals, 1963-1964 (Box 254)
    - Training, stateside (Box 255)
    - Training programs (Box 255)
    - Training programs, 1968 (Box 255)
  - Peru, Lima (Box 255)
  - Philippines
    - General, 3 folders (Box 255)
    - "Lanao Progress", 1933-1934; 2 folders (Box 256)
    - New literates, materials for (Box 256)
    - "Totwl", 1930-1933 (Box 256)
  - Population, world (Box 256)
  - Price lists for books, 1966 (Box 256)
  - Primer illustrations, Sabo, Joe (Box 256)
  - Primers and follow-up materials (Box 256)
  - Primers, lists of, 1962 (Box 256)
  - Project needs (Box 256)
  - Projects, miscellaneous information (Box 256)
  - Projects, lists of (Box 256)
  - Projects, report on a survey of (Box 256)
  - Projects and sponsors (Box 256)
  - Promotional materials, project needs (Box 262)
  - Proposals, "Adult Literacy Training in Underdeveloped Areas of the Free World"
    - [General] (Box 256)
    - Afghanistan (Box 257)
    - Brazil (Box 257)
    - Colombia, 3 folders (Box 257)
    - Colombian Literacy Project (Box 257)
    - Dominican Republic, 1964 (Box 257)
    - Ecuador (Box 257)
    - Mexico, for Production Center of Spanish Literacy Materials, 1963 (Box 257)
    - New literates, newspapers far (Box 257)
    - Nigeria (Box 257)
    - Overseas Study Program (Box 257)
    - Pakistan (Box 257)
    - Research (Box 257)
    - Technical Services Overseas c.1963 (Box 258)
    - Technical Services, United States Government, 1963 (Box 258)
  - Proposals, discussions re (Box 258)
  - Proposals, miscellaneous (Box 258)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 258)
  - Radio (Box 258)
  - Radio School, 1963 (Box 258)
  - Requests for aid, 1959-1963 (Box 258)
  - Somali Republic, data sheet, 1962 (Box 258)
  - Soviet Union, clippings (Box 258)
  - Spain (Box 258)
  - Spanish "Ladder of Literacy" book (Box 258)
  - Spanish literacy material (Box 258)
  - Spanish vocabulary (Box 258)
  - Standards for programs (Box 258)
  - Students, foreign, Africa (Box 258)
  - Students, international (Box 258)
  - Syria (Box 258)
  - Taiwan, 2 folders (Box 258)
  - Teaching aids, Persian and Moro (Box 258)
  - Teaching packages, Portuguese (Box 258)
  - Television literacy, reports and information re (Box 258)
  - Television spots, frames for (Box 262)
  - Thailand (Box 259)
  - Tours
    - Africa, 1963 (Box 259)
    - Boyer, Gilbert (Box 259)
    - Central American fact-finding trip, 1964 (Box 259)
    - Congo (Box 259)
    - General (Box 259)
    - Pakistan and Africa, Marshall Clark, 1961 (Box 259)
    - Warlow, Loretta (Box 259)
    - World Literacy, 1954; "disagreement on World Tour; viewpoint of principals involved and relation to UNESCO; basic to understanding formation lf Laubach Literacy Int. in 1955" (Box 328B)
    - World Literacy, 1960 (Box 259)
  - Tours, 'round the world, 1961-1962 (Box 259)
  - Travel report, 1960 (Box 259)
  - Travel reports, general (Box 259)
  - Trips
    - Literacy Project Survey (Box 259)
    - Mason, David, 1964 (Box 259)
    - Warlow, Loretta, 1960 (Box 259)
  - Turkey, 1960 (Box 259)
  - U.N.E.S.C.O. Project, Kenya, 1962 (Box 259)
  - United Nations (Box 259)
  - University's Role in Latin American Development, 1962 (Box 259)
  - U.S. Government
    - Agency for International Development, 4 folders (Box 260)
    - International Cooperation Administration, 2 folders (Box 260)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 260)
    - State, Department of (Box 261)
  - World Education (Box 261)
  - World tours, 1960 (Box 261)
  - World tours, Laubach Literacy Team (Box 261)
  - Vietnam (Box 261)
- Languages
  - Afrikaans, South Africa (Box 263)
  - Ahanta, Ghana (Box 263)
  - Akha, Burma (Box 263)
  - Amharic, Ethiopia (Box 263)
  - Amis, Taiwan (Box 263)
  - Ao-Assam, India (Box 263)
  - Arabic
    - Egypt, 2 folders (Box 263)
    - Egypt (oversize) (Box 291)
    - Lebanon (Box 263)
    - Palestine and Syria (Box 263)
    - Sudan (Box 263)
    - Tripoli and Algeria, 2 folders (Box 264)
  - Assamese, India (Box 264)
  - Aymara, Bolivia, 2 folders (Box 264)
  - Bali-British Cameroons (Box 264)
  - Bambara (Box 264)
  - Bantu (Box 264)
  - Bandi, Liberia (Box 264)
  - Baouli, Ivory Coast (Box 264)
  - Bari, Sudan (Box 264)
  - Bari, Philippines (oversize) (Box 291)
  - Bassa, Liberia (oversize) (Box 291)
  - Batonu, Nigeria (Box 265)
  - Bemba, Zambia (oversize) (Box 291)
  - Bengali (Box 265)
  - Bengali, India, 2 folders (Box 265)
  - Bicol, Philippines (Box 265)
  - Bilaan, Philippines (Box 265)
  - Bolobo, Belgian Congo (Box 265)
  - Bulu
    - Camerouns (Box 265)
    - Kenya (Box 265)
  - Bura, Nigeria (Box 265)
  - Burmese, Burma (Box 265)
  - Busanchi, Nigeria (Box 265)
  - Bwikalebwe, Belgian Congo (Box 265)
  - Cebuano, Philippines (Box 266)
  - Chattisharhi, India (Box 266)
  - Chinese
    - [General] (Box 266)
    - Homer Dubs system of writing, 3 folders (Box 266)
    - Hong Kong (oversize) (Box 291)
    - Mandarin (Box 266)
    - National phonetic signs, syllabary of (Box 266)
  - Chinyanja, Northern Rhodesia (Box 266)
  - Chokwe, Angola (Box 266)
  - Cigogo, Tanganyika (Box 266)
  - Cishanga, Mozambique (Box 266)
  - Cree, U.S. Indian (Box 266)
  - Creole, Haiti, 3 folders (Box 267)
  - Creole, Haiti (oversize) (Box 291)
  - Dagaari, Gold Coast (Box 267)
  - Dagbani, Gold Coast (Box 267)
  - Dho-Luo, Kenya (Box 267)
  - Dinka, Sudan (Box 267)
  - Douala, Camerouns (Box 267)
  - Engliddish, 2 folders (Box 268)
  - English
    - for Africans and Indians (Box 268)
    - for Africans and Indians (oversize) (Box 291)
    - American, beginning (Box 268)
    - New literates (Box 268)
    - Television, WKNO (Box 268)
  - English, Streamlined, 3 folders (Box 268)
  - English, Jamaica (oversize), 2 folders (Box 291)
  - English, Liberia (Box 268)
  - English (original), U.S.A., 2 folders (Box 269)
  - Eskimo (Box 269)
  - Ewe
    - Gold Coast, 1948 (Box 269)
    - Togoland (Box 269)
  - Fante, Gold Coast (Box 269)
  - Farsi, Iran (Box 269)
  - Filipino languages, Philippines (Box 269)
  - French
    - [General] (Box 269)
    - [General] (oversize) (Box 291)
    - Algeria (Box 269)
    - Camerouns (Box 269)
    - Haiti (Box 269)
    - Mali (Box 269)
  - Fulani, Camerouns (Box 269)
  - Ga, Gold Coast (Box 269)
  - Gio, Liberia (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Gitanga, Mozambique (Box 269)
  - Gola, Liberia (Box 269)
  - Gondi, India (Box 269)
  - Grebo, Liberia (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Guarani, Paraguay (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Gujarati, India (Box 269)
  - Gujarati, India (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Gurmukhi, India (Box 269)
  - Haka, Burma Hindi (Box 269)
  - Hausa, Nigeria (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Hindi, India (Box 269)
  - Hindi, India (oversize), 3 folders (Box 292)
  - Huichol, Mexico (Box 269)
  - Iban, Sarawak, 3 folders (Box 270)
  - Ibo, Nigeria (Box 270)
  - Ibo, Nigeria (oversize) (Box 292)
  - Ifugao, Philippines (Box 270)
  - Igbo, Nigeria (Box 271)
  - Ilango, Philippines (Box 271)
  - Ilocano, Philippines (oversize) (Box 293)
  - Ilyamba, Tanganyika (Box 271)
  - Indebele, Rhodesia (Box 272)
  - Indian, Mexico, 2 folders (Box 272)
  - Indonesian, Indonesia, 2 folders (Box 272)
  - Iramba (Box 272)
  - Italian (Box 272)
  - Javanese, Indonesia (Box 272)
  - Jita (Kijita), Tanganyika (Box 272)
  - Joloano, Philippines (Box 272)
  - Kabre, Togo (Box 272)
  - Kabyle, Afghanistan (Box 272)
  - Kachin, Burma (Box 273)
  - Kaka, French Camerouns (Box 273)
  - Kalenjin, Kenya (Box 273)
  - Kamba, Kenya (Box 273)
  - Kanarese, India (Box 273)
  - Kaonde, Zambia (Box 273)
  - Kekchi, Mexico (Box 273)
  - Kasem, Ghana (Box 273)
  - Khasi, Asam, India (Box 273)
  - Kihungana, Belgian Congo (Box 273)